# Judi L. Johnson

2285 NW Putnam Road Bend, OR 97701 (330) 283-3359

www.linkedin.com/pub/judij35 iudij35@amail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Award winning Sales Executive with strong business development skills and experience. Successful record of promoting business growth. Over 20 years in sales, marketing, event planning and fundraising. Over 15 combined years of sales experience in high technology as a Major Account Executive and Enterprise Sales Executive for companies such as Sprint Business, and Partners of Cisco Systems, Microsoft, IBM/Lotus Notes. Seeking an opportunity in my areas of expertise where I can fully utilize my skills.

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Customer Relations
Consultative Solution Sales
Results driven Sales Director
Channel Development & Growth

Influential Public Speaker Staff Training & Development Technology Sales & Corporate rollouts Microsoft Office Programs & CRM Database

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Program Director**

Northeastern, OH

North Castle Partners dba JC USA, Inc.

2007-2015

- Provided leadership and oversight of division sales team and generated brand awareness campaigns.
- Responsible for planning, executing and launching new business in assigned territory, exceeding company expectations.
- Created speeches, sales scripts and promotional marketing that were used company wide.
- Presented wellness program benefits at corporations and health fairs.
- Managed territory budgets, strategized on business development which resulted in achievement of 10% market growth.
- Awarded "Program Director of the Year." Continuously exceeded monthly quota.

**Consultant**Arbonne International

Laguna Beach, CA
2005-2007

- Acted as a Sales Manager for health and skin care product line by training, developing and managing a staff of 12 sales associates.
- Worked closely with Regional Vice President to develop territory growth.
- Gave presentations at networking events.
- Increased new business and sales base by over 125% each month.

# **Major Account Manager**

Los Angeles, CA 2002-2005 PC Gov

• Developed and managed technical sales for government accounts

- Assisted government agencies in achieving strategic IT goals by creating forecasting strategies.
- Streamlined procedures for contract approval and quote procedures.

# **Independent Business Consultant**

Los Angeles, CA

Olson & Kotowski

2001-2002

- Analyzed and improved departmental operations resulting in increased productivity and sales.
- Trained and mentored staff with methods to develop existing accounts and grow new business.
- Developed monitoring methods, procedures and progress reports for "C" level officers.
- Created a software program for company based intranet to guide sales team through the sales cycle.

## **Major Account Manager**

Irvine, CA

Ascolta, Cisco Business Partner

2000-2001

- Managed the technical training, certifications, classroom and e-learning solutions of 25 fortune 100 and 500 companies.
- Sales and implementation of Cisco technical training for companies such as Walt Disney, Verizon, AT & T and the Los Angeles Times/Time Mirror Company.
- Managed corporate training rollouts for IT staff and end-users of up to 17,000 employees.
- Supervised instructor staff and utilized analytics to ensure user experience is best in class.
- Finished most months over 200% of guota.
- "Presidents Club" and "Top Rep for the City of Los Angeles."
- Managed the Los Angeles Cisco User Group Meetings and programs.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA - Major: Communications/Public Relations Stephens College, Columbia, MO – Major: Communications, Minor: Psychology